Finding aid for the William Bast papers LSC.2290
UCLA Library Special Collections
William Bast papers
1956-2005
UCLA Library Special Collections
Bast, William
LSC.2290
44.4 linear feet (111 boxes)
William Bast was a television and film writer, as well as a friend and biographer of James Dean. The William Bast papers consists largely of scripts written over the course of more than forty years.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: This collection contains processed audiovisual materials. All requests to access digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Paul Huson, 2015.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9980247583606533
Biography/History
William Bast was born in Wisconsin in 1931. While attending college at UCLA he shared an apartment with James Dean. Later, he and Dean moved to New York City independently of one another and roomed together there as well. In 1956, a year after the actor's death, Bast published the first biography of Dean. In the 1960s Bast began writing for television, both in Hollywood and in London. He worked in a variety of genres, including medical dramas (Ben Casey), science fiction (The Outer Limits), and crime shows (Hawaii Five-O). In the 1980s he created, with his partner Paul Huson, the short-lived series Tucker's Witch and The Colbys, a spin-off the wildly popular program Dynasty. Bast and Huson continued their collaboration throughout the 1990s, writing several television movies. In 2006 Bast published a second biography, Surviving James Dean, in which he revealed that their relationship had occasionally been sexual in nature. William Bast died in Los Angeles on May 4, 2015.
Scope and Content
The collection consists mostly of scripts written by William Bast across his career, both produced and unproduced. Projects from early in his career tend to be represented by only a single script, while later projects often have several drafts, some heavily annotated. These later projects are often accompanied by agreements, research material, and some production documents. There is a very small amount of personal correspondence. There is also very little about James Dean, and most of what is present is in the context of the television movie based on Bast's first biography.
Organization and Arrangement
The collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1. Television productions
Series 2. Feature film productions
Series 3. Unproduced material
Series 4. General files
Metadata Rights Declaration
Finding aid description and metadata in this record are licensed under a Creative Commons Public Domain Designation (CC0 1.0 Universal). See LSC's Metadata Rights Statement for more information.
Screenwriters -- Archives.; Television writers -- Archives.; Television scripts; Bast, William -- Archives
- Series 1. Television productions, 1960-2001
  General
  Unless otherwise noted, all scripts and script material are by William Bast.
  Organization and Arrangement
  Titles are in alphabetical order. Within each title, script material is listed first, in chronological order. Additional materials are then listed in alphabetical order.
  - Acapulco (NBC, 1961)
    - Teleplay "Blood Money", March 17, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Scope and Content
      Includes outline.
  - The Alfred Hitchock Hour (CBS/NBC, 1962-1965)
    - Teleplay "One of the Family" by Oscar Millard and William Best, based on a story by James Yaffe, October 9, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Amelia Earhart (NBC, 1976)
    - Story outline by Robert Getchell, May 17, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Story outline, December 30, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - First draft teleplay, March 14, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Teleplay, June 27, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Teleplay Amelia by Carol Sobieski, September 16, 1975-April 1, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Research, 1935-1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Writers Guild of America, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Scope and Contents
      Contains correspondence regarding credit arbitration [sole credit was awarded to Carol Sobieski].
  - Apple's Way (CBS, 1974-1975)
    - Final draft teleplay "The Musician", December 28, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Final draft teleplay "The Engagement", July 21, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Ben Casey (ABC, 1961-1966)
    - Outlines, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Teleplay "But Linda Only Smiled", undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Final draft teleplay "But Linda Only Smiled", undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Final revised teleplay "But Linda Only Smiled", August 9, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Final teleplay "Dark Night for Billy Harris" by Gabrielle Upton and William Bast, October 12, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - The Big One: The Great Los Angeles Earthquake (NBC, 1990)
    - Story outlines by William Bast and Paul Huson, May 15, 1989-October, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - First draft teleplay by William Bast and Paul Huson, part one, October 27, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      FILE CONTAINS DIGITAL MATERIALS: To review these digital materials, you must notify the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk in advance of your visit.
      Includes 5.25" floppy disk "Typed first draft."
    - First draft teleplay by William Bast and Paul Huson, part two, October 27, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Teleplay by William Bast and Paul Huson, part one [heavily annotated], undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Teleplay by William Bast and Paul Huson, part two [heavily annotated], undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Revised second draft teleplay Countdown by William Bast & Paul Huson and Michael Petryni, part one [heavily annotated], March 26, 1990-June 12, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Revised second draft teleplay Countdown by William Bast & Paul Huson and Michael Petryni, part two [heavily annotated], April 2, 1990-June 26, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Agreements, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Breakdown, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Publicity, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      Includes note from Warren Littlefield.
    - Writers Guild of America, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      Contains material regarding credit arbitration.
  - Born Innocent (NBC, 1974)
    - First draft teleplay, March 14, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Revised first draft teleplay, March 29, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Second draft teleplay by Gerald DiPego, July 18, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Legal, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      Includes material regarding credit arbitration [Gerald Di Pego received sole credit].
  - Bus Stop (ABC, 1961-1962)
    - Teleplay "What Does Charlie Think?", undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Circle of Fear (NBC, 1972-1973)
    - Teleplay "Mariah", June 23, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      Biography/History
      Broadcast as "Cry of the Cat."
  - The Colbys (ABC, 1985-1987)
    - Step outline "The Celebration" [annotated], June 5, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Final draft teleplay "The Celebration" by William Bast & Paul Huson, August 22, 1985-September 6, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      Includes cast list.
    - Story outline "Conspiracy of Silence" by William Bast and Paul Huson [annotated], July 10, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Final draft teleplay "Conspiracy of Silence" by Dennis Turner, from a story by William Bast and Paul Huson, September 5, 1985-September 13, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Story outline "Moment of Truth" by William Bast and Paul Huson [annotated], July 24, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Final draft teleplay "Moment of Truth" by William Bast and Paul Huson, September 12, 1985-September 23, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Story outline "Family Album" by William Bast and Paul Huson, June 18, 1985-August 5, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Final draft teleplay "Family Album" by Rick Edelstein & Dennis Turner, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, September 23, 1985-October 2, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Story outline "Shadow of the Past" by William Bast & Paul Huson [annotated], July 1, 1985-September 10, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Final draft teleplay "Shadow of the Past" by Dennis Turner, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, October 2, 1985-October 11. 1985 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Step outline "A House Divided" by William Bast & Paul Huson [annotated], July 19, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Final draft teleplay "A House Divided" by Frank Furino, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, October 11, 1985-October 17, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Story outline "The Reunion" by William Bast & Paul Huson, August 19, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Teleplay "The Reunion" by Frank Furino, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, October 23, 1985-Octber 29, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Story outline "Fallen Idol" by William Bast & Paul Huson, August 30, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Final draft teleplay "Fallen Idol" by Oliver Clark, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, October 31, 1985-November 13, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Story outline "The Letter" by William Bast & Paul Huson, September 9, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Final draft teleplay "The Letter" by Doris Silverton, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, November 12, 1985-November 22, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Story outline "The Turning Point" by William Bast & Paul Huson, September 27, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Final draft teleplay "The Turning Point" by Chuck Pratt, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, November 20, 1985-December 4, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      Includes cast list
    - Story outline "Thursday's Child" by William Bast & Paul Huson, October 14, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Final draft teleplay "Thursday's Child" by Rick Edelstein, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, December 3, 1985-December 11, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Story outline "The Pact" by William Bast & Paul Huson, October 25, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Final draft teleplay "The Pact" by Dennis Turner, from a story William Bast & Paul Huson, December 20, 1985-December 24, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Story outline "Fallon's Choice" by William Bast & Paul Huson, November 11, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Final draft teleplay "Fallon's Choice" by Doris Silverton, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, December 23, 1985-December 30, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Story outline "The Trial" by William Bast & Paul Huson, November 22, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Final draft teleplay "The Trial" by Donald Paul Roos, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, December 30, 1985-January 14, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Story outline "Burden of Proof" by William Bast & Paul Huson, December 2, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Final draft teleplay "Burden of Proof" by Dennis Turner, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, January 2, 1986-January 16, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Story outline "My Father's House" by William Bast & Paul Huson, December 13, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Final draft teleplay "My Father's House" by Frank V. Furino, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, January 15, 1986-January 22, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Story outline "The Outcast" by William Bast & Paul Huson, December 27, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Final draft teleplay "The Outcast" by Donald Paul Roos, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, January 22, 1986-February 3, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Story outline "The Wedding" by William Bast & Paul Huson, January 16, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Final draft teleplay "The Wedding" by Frank V. Furino, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, January 30, 1986-February 13, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Story outline "The Honeymoon" by William Bast & Paul Huson, January 23, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Final draft teleplay "The Honeymoon" by Maryanne Kasica & Michael Scheff, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, February 18, 1986-February 19, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Story outline "Double Jeopardy" by William Bast & Paul Huson, February 3, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Final draft teleplay "Double Jeopardy" by Doris Silverton, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, February 24, 1986-March 5, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Story outline "A Family Affair" by William Bast & Paul Huson, February 11, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Final draft teleplay "A Family Affair" by Donald Paul Roos, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, March 4, 1986-March 11, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Story outline "The Reckoning" by William Bast & Paul Huson, February 13, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Final draft teleplay "The Reckoning" by Dennis Turner, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, March 11, 1986-March 24, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Story outline "Anniversary Waltz" by William Bast & Paul Huson, February 19, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Final draft teleplay "Anniversary Waltz" by Donald Paul Roos, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, March 20, 1986-March 26, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Story outline "Checkmate" by William Bast & Paul Huson, February 21, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Final draft teleplay "Checkmate" by William Bast & Paul Huson, April 1, 1986-April 8, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Story outline "The Gathering Storm" by William Bast & Paul Huson, May 14, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Final draft teleplay "The Gathering Storm" by William Bast & Paul Huson, July 7, 1986-July 14, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Story outline "No Exit" by William Bast & Paul Huson, May 15, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Final draft teleplay "No Exit" by Donald Paul Roos, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, July 15, 1986-July 28, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Story outline "Turnabout" by William Bast & Paul Huson, May 27, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Final draft teleplay "Turnabout" by Frank V. Furino, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, July 28, 1986-July 31, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Story outline "The Matchmaker" by William Bast & Paul Huson, June 4, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Final draft teleplay by "The Matchmaker" by William Bast & Paul Huson, August 1, 1986-August 7, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Story outline "Something Old, Something New" by William Bast & Paul Huson, June 10, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Final draft teleplay "Something Old, Something New" by Donald Paul Roos, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, August 12, 1986-August 18, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Story outline "The Gala" by William Bast & Paul Huson, June 30, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Final draft teleplay "The Gala" by Dennis Turner, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, August 21, 1986-August 27, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Story outline "Bloodlines" by William Bast & Paul Huson, July 10, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Final draft teleplay "Bloodlines" by Dennis Turner, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, August 28, 1986-September 12, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Story outline "Deceptions" by William Bast & Paul Huson, July 24, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Final draft teleplay "Deceptions" by Carol Saraceno, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, September 9, 1986-September 19, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Story outline "And Baby Makes Four" by William Bast & Paul Huson, August 4, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Final draft teleplay "And Baby Makes Four" by Mart Crowley, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, September 17, 1986-September 25, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Story outline "Bid for Freedom" by William Bast & Paul Huson, August 14, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Final draft teleplay "Bid for Freedom" by Dennis Turner, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, September 26, 1986-October 2, 1986. (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Story outline "Sanctuary" by William Bast & Paul Huson, August 25, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Final draft teleplay "Sanctuary" by Carol Saraceno, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, October 6, 1986-October 15, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Story outline "Reaching Out" by William Bast & Paul Huson, September 5, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Final draft teleplay "Reaching Out" by Donald Paul Roos, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, October 14, 1986-October 29, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Story outline "Power Plays" by William Bast & Paul Huson, September 18, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Final draft teleplay "Power Plays" by Jeff Smith, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, October 24, 1986-Movember 5, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Story outline "The Legacy" by William Bast & Paul Huson, September 26, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Final draft teleplay "The Legacy" by Dennis Turner, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, October 31, 1986-November 12, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Story outline "The Home-Wrecker" by William Bast & Paul Huson, October 1, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Final draft teleplay "The Home-Wrecker" by Carol Saraceno, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, November 3, 1986-December 11, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Story outline "Manhunt" by William Bast & Paul Huson, October 6, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Final draft teleplay "Manhunt" by Doris Silverton, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, November 7, 1986-November 17, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Story outline "All Fall Down" by William Bast & Paul Huson, October 13, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Final draft teleplay "All Fall Down" by Dennis Turner, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, November 10, 1986-December 23, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Story outline "Guilty Party" by William Bast & Paul Huson, October 22, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Final draft teleplay "Guilty Party" by Dennis Turner, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, November 20, 1986-January 14, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Story outline "Fallon's Baby" by William Bast & Paul Huson, November 4, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Final draft teleplay "Fallon's Baby" by Frank V. Furino, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, December 4, 1986-December 5, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Story outline "Answered Payers" by William Bast & Paul Huson, November 17, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Final draft teleplay "Answered Payers" by Donald Paul Roos, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, December 19, 1986-December 24, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Story outline "Return Engagement" by William Bast & Paul Huson, November 25, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Final draft teleplay "Return Engagement" by Elliott Lewis, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, December 31, 1986-January 9, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Story outline "Devil's Advocate" by William Bast & Paul Huson, December 9, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Final draft teleplay "Devil's Advocate" by Mart Crowley, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, January 9, 1987-January 21, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Story outline "Betrayals" by William Bast & Paul Huson, December 26, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Final draft teleplay "Betrayals" by Carol Saraceno, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, January 20, 1987-January 29, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Story outline "Dead End" by William Bast & Paul Huson, January 8, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Final draft teleplay "Dead End" by Donald Paul Roos, from a story by William Bast & Paul Huson, January 28, 1987-February 2, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Story outline "Crossroads" by William Bast & Paul Huson, January 19, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Final draft teleplay "Crossroads" by William Bast & Paul Huson, February 6, 1987-February 17, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Agreements, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 9-10)
    - Awards, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 11)
      Includes material regarding the People's Choice Awards, 1986.
    - Calendars, 1985-1987 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - "Chuck's Notes", undated (Box 11, Folder 2-5)
      Contains script pages for second season episodes annotated by Charlton Heston.
    - Correspondence, 1985-1989 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      Includes: note from Aaron Spelling; handwritten note from Tracy Scoggins; memo regarding the use of Barbara Stanwyck's image after she left the show; diagnostic report on viewers' opinions about the program.
    - Dispute, 1985-1989 (Box 12, Folder 2-3)
      Contains material regarding payment for Colbys characters "spun back" to Dynasty.
    - Dynastygram, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 4)
      Contains issues of a fanzine about Dynasty, written by "a guy on Sports Illustrated."
    - Finale, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 5)
      Contains material, including storyboards, regarding the series' final scene, in which a character boards a flying saucer.
    - Heston, Charlton - correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Memorabilia, 1985-1987 (Box 12, Folder 7)
      Includes dress and protocol instructions for a luncheon with the royal family of Monaco.
    - Periodicals, 1985-1986 (Box 12, Folder 8)
      Contains: TV Guide, Nov. 16, 1985 and Sept. 13, 1986; Vanity Fair, June, 1985; Los Angeles, September, 1985.
    - Production file, 1985-1986 (Box 13, Folder 1)
      Includes casting suggestions; cast lists, shooting schedules, directories for Aaron Spellings Productions.
    - Publicity, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Ratings, 1985-1987 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Research, 1984-1985 (Box 13, Folder 4)
      Contains: Dynasty: The Authorized Biography of the Carringtons (Garden City: Doubleday); Forbes, vol. 11, no. 136.
    - Research, 1985-1986 (Box 13, Folder 5)
      Includes material on ballet dancers, space stations, pregnancy, and a variety of other topics; transcript for the July 29, 1986 episode of ABC News Nightline "Soviet Space"; handwritten note from Charlton Heston.
    - Residuals, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Sets, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Story ideas, undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
      Consists mostly of notes on index cards.
    - Story projections, 1985-1986 (Box 14, Folder 4-8, Box 15, Folder 1-2)
      Includes show bibles, proposed storylines, notes.
    - Telephone register, 1985-1986 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Combat! (ABC, 1962-1967)
    - Teleplay "Just for the Record", May 29, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Revised final draft teleplay "Entombed" by Paul Playdon and Bob Frederick, from a story by William Bast, October 22, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Development, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 6)
      Includes a letter from Robert Blees about technical advice from the U.S. Army; character descriptions.
  - Deadly Invasion: The Killer Bee Nightmare (Fox, 1995)
    - First draft teleplay "Killer Bees" by William Bast & Paul Huson, June 10, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - First revised teleplay "Killer Bees" by William Bast & Paul Huson, September 14, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Second draft teleplay "Deadly Invasion" by William Bast & Paul Huson [annotated], September 24, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Second revised draft teleplay "Deadly Invasion" by William Bast & Paul Huson, May 3, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Shooting draft teleplay "Natural Enemies" by William Bast & Paul Huson, rewrite by Rockne S. O'Bannon, September 9, 1994-September 23, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1992-1995 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Writers Guild of America, 1992-1995 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      Contains material regarding credit arbitration, including story outlines.
  - Dr. Kildare (NBC, 1961-1966)
    - Teleplay "The Twins", undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
      Includes outlines and research material [broadcast as "The Dark Side of the Mirror"].
  - The First Olympics: Athens 1896 (NBC, 1984)
    - First draft teleplay, part two by Charles Gary Allison [annotated], August 23, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Second draft teleplay [no writer credited], December 20, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - First draft teleplay, part one by William Bast, from a story by Charles Gary Allison and William Bast [annotated], May 23, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 8)